<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Suhas G</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Suhas G</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:47:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nouns</title>
      <link>/learning/german/nouns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 00:47:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learning/german/nouns/</guid>
      <description>  Noun Plural Meaning      Die Frau  Die Frauen  The woman    Der Herr  Die Herren  The man/ Mr    Der Mann  Die Männer  The man    Das Kind  Die Kinder  The child    Der Student  Die Studenten  The student    Das Buch  Die Bücher  The Book    Die Lampe  Die Lampen  The Lamp    Der Bliestift  Die Bleistifte  The Pencil    Der Kugelschreiber  Die Kugelschreiber  The Ballpoint Pen    Der Kursraum  Die Kursräume  The Courseroom    Das Heft  Die Hefte  The Notebook/ The booklet    Der Block  Die Blöcke/ Die Blocks  The writing pad    Das Glas  Die Gläser  The Glass (as in tumbler)    Die Tasche  Die Taschen  The Bag    Die Tasse  Die Tassen  The Cup    Der Laptop  Die Laptops  The Laptop    Der Schuh  Die Schuhe  The Shoe    Das Zimmer  Die Zimmer  The Room    Die Nummer  Die Nummern  The Number    Die Dame  Die Damen  The Lady    Die Toilette  Die Toiletten  The Toilet    Die Tür  Die Türen  The Door    Die Information  Die Informationen  The Information/The Reception    Die Cafeteria  Die Cafeterias/ Die Cafeterien  The Cafeteria    Die Sprachschule  Die Sprachschulen  The Language School    Die Klasse  Die Klassen  The Class    Der Schüler  Die Schüler  The Student    Der Lehrer  Die Lehrer  The Teacher (Male)    Die Lehrerin  Die Lehrerinnen  The Teacher (Female)    Die Seite  Die Sieten  The Page    Der Stühl  Die Stühle  The Chair (Stool)    Die Tafel  Die Tafeln  The Blackboard    Das Bild  Die Bilder  The Picture / The Painting    Der Tisch  Die Tische  The Table    Das Sofa  Die Sofas  The Sofa    Das Regal  Die Regale  The Rack/The Shelf    Die Vase  Die Vasen  The Vase    Der Teppich  Die Teppiche  The Carpet    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Pronouns and Possessives</title>
      <link>/learning/german/personal-pronouns-and-possessives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 21:02:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learning/german/personal-pronouns-and-possessives/</guid>
      <description>Similar to how articles change form by different cases, pronouns and possessives also change form. Lets see how each of them look.
Personal Pronouns Pronouns are used in place of nouns to avoid repitition. These pronouns in Nominative, Accusative and Dative are shown in the below table. As for Genitive, we have seen that Genitive is used to indicate possession. And possessives do just that. So what&amp;rsquo;s the difference? Apparently, Genitive could have had been used for other things as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Articles</title>
      <link>/learning/german/articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 18:41:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learning/german/articles/</guid>
      <description>In German, similar to English we have Definite and Indefinite articles. But unlike English, these articles change form depending on the gender and also case (as we saw in The 4 cases in German).
Definite Article We use a definite article when we are addressing a specific noun, when there is only one of that kind, when referring to an object already mentioned. In German, the definite article can be in follwing forms depending on gender and the case in which the noun is used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 4 Cases in German</title>
      <link>/learning/german/cases-in-german/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 16:17:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learning/german/cases-in-german/</guid>
      <description>First things first.
I learnt the explanation for the below from the following Youtube video: Understand the GERMAN CASES - Accusative, Dative, Nominative, Genitive  and the book German for Dummies
 In German, the position of words can be interchanged while still retaining the same meaning.
For eg. Der Hund beißt den Mann can be written as Den Mann beißt der Hund. Both mean the same (The dog bites the man), unlike english, where the literal translation becomes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noun Genders</title>
      <link>/learning/german/noun-genders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 22:55:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learning/german/noun-genders/</guid>
      <description>In German, nouns can be in 3 genders- Masculine, Feminine, Neuter. The classification of nouns to different genders isn&amp;rsquo;t solely based on meaning (unfortunately), but there are some general rules which can be followed to identify the gender for a given noun (usually, and as always there are exceptions). Much of the stuff below I have taken from Gender of Nouns in German grammar
Masculine Nouns  Indicator  Examples    Male People Mann, Präsident  Seasons of the year Frühling, Sommer, Herbst  Days Sonntag, Montag, Dienstag, Mittwoch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Question words</title>
      <link>/learning/german/question_words/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 22:15:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learning/german/question_words/</guid>
      <description>Question Word  Meaning  Example  Example Meaning    Wer Who Wer bist du? Who are you?  Wie How Wie geht&amp;#39;s? How are you?  Woher From where/Where from Woher kommt ihr? Where do you come from?  Wo Where Wo leigt Polen? Where is Poland?(Where is Poland located?)  Was What Was ist das? What is that?  Wann When Wann ist dein Geburstag?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verbs</title>
      <link>/learning/german/verbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 20:49:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learning/german/verbs/</guid>
      <description>  Verb Meaning Verb Forms     sein to be Conjugate   sein   Ich bin   Du bist   Er/Es/Sie ist   Wir sind   Ihr seid   Sie/sie sind        heissen to be called Conjugate   heissen   Ich heisse   Du heisst   Er/Es/Sie heisst   Wir heissen   Ihr heisst   Sie/sie heissen        kommen to come Conjugate   kommen   Ich komme   Du kommst   Er/Es/Sie kommt   Wir kommen   Ihr kommt   Sie/sie kommen        gehen to go Conjugate   gehen   Ich gehe   Du gehst   Er/Es/Sie geht   Wir gehen   Ihr geht   Sie/sie gehen        leigen to be located Conjugate   leigen   Ich leige   Du leigst   Er/Es/Sie leigt   Wir leigen   Ihr leigt   Sie/sie leigen        lernen to learn Conjugate   lernen   Ich lerne   Du lernst   Er/Es/Sie lernt   Wir lernen   Ihr lernt   Sie/sie lernen        haben to have Conjugate   haben   Ich habe   Du hast   Er/Es/Sie hat   Wir haben   Ihr habt   Sie/sie haben        machen to do Conjugate   machen   Ich mache   Du machst   Er/Es/Sie macht   Wir machen   Ihr macht   Sie/sie machen        arbeiten to work Conjugate   arbeiten   Ich arbeite   Du arbeitest   Er/Es/Sie arbeitet   Wir arbeiten   Ihr arbeitet   Sie/sie arbeiten        schreiben to write Conjugate   schreiben   Ich schreibe   Du schreibst   Er/Es/Sie schreibt   Wir schreiben   Ihr schreibt   Sie/sie schreiben        telefonieren to call (phone) Conjugate   telefonieren   Ich telefoniere   Du telefonierst   Er/Es/Sie telefoniert   Wir telefonieren   Ihr telefoniert   Sie/sie telefonieren        kopieren to copy Conjugate   kopieren   Ich kopiere   Du kopierst   Er/Es/Sie kopiert   Wir kopieren   Ihr kopiert   Sie/sie kopieren        studieren to study Conjugate   studieren   Ich studiere   Du studierst   Er/Es/Sie studiert   Wir studieren   Ihr studiert   Sie/sie studieren        funktionieren to function Conjugate   funktionieren   Ich funktioniere   Du funktionierst   Er/Es/Sie funktioniert   Wir funktionieren   Ihr funktioniert   Sie/sie funktionieren        suchen to search Conjugate   suchen   Ich suche   Du suchst   Er/Es/Sie sucht   Wir suchen   Ihr sucht   Sie/sie suchen         </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numbers in German</title>
      <link>/learning/german/numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 23:59:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learning/german/numbers/</guid>
      <description>Numbers from 0 to 10  Number Number in Words    0 Null  1 Eins  2 Zwei  3 Drei  4 Vier  5 Fünf  6 Sechs  7 Seiben  8 Acht  9 Neun  10 Zehn    Numbers from 11 to 20  Number Number in Words    11 Elf  12 Zwölf  13 Dreizehn  14 Vierzehn  15 Fünfzehn  16 Sechzehn  17 Seibzehn  18 Achtzehn  19 Neunzehn  20 Zwanzing    Numbers from 21 to 30  Number Number in Words    21 Einsundzwanzig  22 Zweiundzwanzig  23 Dreiundzwanzig  24 Vierundzwanzig  25 Fünfundzwanzig  26 Sechsundzwanzig  27 Seibenundzwanzig  28 Achtundzwanzig  29 Neunundzwanzig  30 Dreiẞig    Tens from 30 to 90  Number Number in Words    30 Dreẞig  40 Vierzig  50 Fünfzig  60 Sechzig  70 Siebzig  80 Achtzig  90 Neunzig    Others  Number Number in Words    100 Einhundert  1000 Eintausend  100000 Einhunderttausend    Usage  Number Number in Words    101 Hunderteins  111 Hundertelf  120 Hundertzwanzig  131 Hunderteindreiẞig  152.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alphabets</title>
      <link>/learning/german/alphabets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 22:16:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/learning/german/alphabets/</guid>
      <description>Alphabets in German and their pronounciation  Alphabet Word Word picture/ Meaning Pronounciation    A Apfel   Apfel     Your browser does not support the audio element.    B Banane   Banane     Your browser does not support the audio element.    C Chor   Chor     Your browser does not support the audio element.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 19:25:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Suhas. I&amp;rsquo;m an Electronics and Communication Engineer with a tremedous amount of interest in Computer Vision, and by extension Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Augmented Reality and all their relatives. On the other hand I&amp;rsquo;m also drawn to art, animation, web design etc.
Someday I want to be part of making all of our Sci-Fi movies a reality! 😎
And this blog is just a way to show what I do in my free time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>